Article starting on page 49.
Industry Representation MCCIA–PMRDA Meet Addresses Industry Issues A focused MCCIA–PMRDA interaction on August 18 brought key industrial issues in the Pirangut–Urawade and Chakan regions before the development authority, covering delayed permissions, road alignments and access, traffic and environmental concerns.
n interaction between the Mahratta Pesh Engineers raised the issue of conduct a joint site inspection to verify A Chamber of Commerce, Industries development permissions pending for more permissions, drainage ownership and and Agriculture (MCCIA) and than two years and repeated demands for possible violations, with coordination with the Pune Metropolitan Region resurvey.
PMRDA officials clarified that the Maharashtra Pollution Control Board Development Authority (PMRDA) on a second measurement was not required (MPCB) where required.
August 18 addressed planning approvals, and said the proposal could be processed The meeting also discussed broader road infrastructure, environmental concerns within 7–10 days after submission of the industrial infrastructure issues, including and other issues affecting industries in the updated Fire NOC.
Officials also informed traffic congestion and encroachments in Pirangut–Urawade and Chakan regions.
The participants that a dedicated cell had been Pirangut, road widening and land acquisition meeting was attended by K. Manjulekshmi, established to expedite industry proposals.
in Chakan and industrial waste management.
Additional Municipal Commissioner, MCCIA presented a sustainable dry-waste PMRDA, senior PMRDA officials and Road Alignment and and recycling model for possible adoption in Access Discussed MCCIA representatives led by Sudhanwa industrial and rural areas.
Kopardekar, Director, MCCIA, with industry Sane Equipments Pvt. Ltd. highlighted a members presenting specific cases for discrepancy between the Regional Plan (RP) Monthly Reviews Planned resolution.
road alignment shown on maps and the actual The meeting concluded with a The interaction resulted in an assurance road alignment at Urawade.
PMRDA clarified commitment to hold monthly industry– from PMRDA to hold regular review that changes to an RP road come under the PMRDA review meetings and undertake meetings to address pending development authority of the Divisional Commissioner prompt site-level action on identified issues.
permissions and improve coordination with and agreed to examine the matter through The proposed mechanism is expected to industry.
Several company-specific cases GIS mapping and the ongoing structural provide industry with a regular platform involving approvals, road alignment, access, planning exercise.
to raise pending planning, permission and drainage and environmental issues were taken Micro Supreme Auto raised discrepancies infrastructure matters with the Authority and up during the meeting.
between successive DP and RP maps and track their resolution.
the lack of a proper approach road to its l Pending Permissions Taken Up Urawade facility.
PMRDA officials agreed to Atrium Innovations, a clean-tech cross-check the relevant GIS layers and survey company operating a DME plant in documents.
collaboration with CSIR-NCL, raised issues Environmental related to permissions for Methanol and Concerns Flagged DME fuel storage.
PMRDA advised the Minilec India raised concerns over company to submit the latest notification, Scan the QR code to unauthorised workshops and sewage and PESO approvals and a revised proposal listen to the gist of the through BPMS and agreed to facilitate chemical discharge into stormwater drains article.
in Pirangut.
PMRDA directed officials to scrutiny of the proposal.
august 2026 | SAMPADA | 49
This article is from Sampada, published by MCCIA.